[静音]
Large language models are very good at transforming its input to a different format,
大型语言模型非常擅长将其输入转换为不同的格式，
such as inputting a piece of text in one language and transforming it or
例如输入一种语言的文本并将其转换或者
translating it to a different language, or
翻译成另一种语言，或者
helping with spelling and grammar corrections.
协助进行拼写和语法纠正。
So taking as input a piece of text that may not be fully grammatical and
输入一段可能不完全符合语法的文本，
helping you to fix that up a bit, or even transforming formats,
让它帮助你稍微修正一下，甚至是转换格式，
such as inputting HTML and outputting JSON.
例如输入HTML，输出JSON。
So there's a bunch of applications that I used to write somewhat painfully with
我曾经开发一些应用程序时比较痛苦，因为用的是
a bunch of regular expressions that would definitely be much more simply implemented
一堆正则表达式。现在肯定可以简单地来实现
now with a large language model and a few prompts.
只需一个大语言模型和几个提示。
Yeah, I use chat-gbt to proofread pretty much everything I write these days.
是的，现在我几乎用ChatGPT来校对我写的所有东西。
So I'm excited to show you some more examples in the notebook now.
所以我很兴奋现在就在Notebook中向你展示更多示例。
So first we'll import OpenAI and also use the same get_Completion helper
首先，我们导入OpenAI，并使用相同的get_Completion辅助函数
function that we've been using throughout the videos.
就像我们在整个视频中那样。
And the first thing we'll do is a translation task.
首先我们将进行一个翻译任务。
So large language models are trained on a lot of text from kind of many sources,
大型语言模型是在许多来源的大量文本上进行训练的，
a lot of which is the Internet.
其中很多是来自于互联网。
And this is kind of, of course, in many different languages.
而这些文本当然是用许多不同的语言编写的。
So this kind of imbues the model with the ability to do translation.
这种方法赋予了模型进行翻译的能力。
And these models know kind of hundreds of languages to varying degrees of
这些模型可以翻译数百种语言，但熟练度不同,
proficiency.
专业程度也不同。
And so we'll go through some examples of how to use this capability.
我们将通过一些示例介绍如何使用这种能力。
So let's start off with something simple.
让我们从简单的事情开始吧。
So in this first example,
在第一个例子中，
the prompt is translate the following English text to Spanish.
提示是将以下英文文本翻译成西班牙语。
Hi, I would like to order a blender.
你好，我想订购一个搅拌机。
And the response is, hola, me gustaría ordenar una licuadora.
回复是，你好，我想订购一个搅拌机。
And I'm very sorry to all of you Spanish speakers,
非常抱歉，对所有的西班牙语使用者，
I never learned Spanish unfortunately, as you can definitely tell.
很遗憾我从未学过西班牙语，你们肯定可以看出的。
Okay, let's try another example.
好的，让我们再试一个例子。
So in this example, the prompt is, tell me what language this is.
在这个例子中，提示是，告诉我这是什么语言。
And then this is in French, combien coûte le lampadaire?
这句话是法语，意思是“这个台灯多少钱？”
And so let's run this.
让我们来运行它。
And the model has identified that this is French.
模型已经确定这是法语了。
The model can also do multiple translations at once.
模型还可以同时进行多个翻译。
So in this example, let's say translate the following text to French and Spanish.
在这个例子中，我们让它将以下文本翻译成法语和西班牙语。
And you know what, let's add another, an English pirate.
你知道吗，让我们再加一个，英语海盗(Facebook上的一种粉丝语)。
And the text is, I want to order a basketball.
这个文本是，“我想订购一个篮球。”
So here we have French, Spanish, and English pirate.
这里我们有法语、西班牙语和英语海盗。
So in some languages, the translation can change depending on the speaker's
有些语言中，翻译的方式可能会因为说话者和听众之间的关系而有所不同。
relationship to the listener.
你可以向语言模型解释这一点，
And you can also explain this to the language model, and
所以它就能够相应地进行翻译了。
so it will be able to kind of translate accordingly.
在这个例子中，我们要求将以下文本翻译成西班牙语，
So in this example, we say, translate the following text to Spanish in both
在这个例子中，我们说，将以下文本翻译成西班牙语。
the formal and informal forms, would you like to order a pillow?
用正式和非正式语调翻译，“你是否想要订购一个枕头吗？”
And also notice here, we're using a different delimiter than these backticks.
请注意，这里我们使用的分隔符，而不是这些反引号不同。
It doesn't really matter as long as it's kind of a clear separation.
只要有一个清晰的分隔即可，其实并不重要。
So here we have the formal and informal.
在这里我们有正式和非正式的形式。
So formal is when you're speaking to someone who's kind of maybe senior to you
正式的情况是当你与某个比你更高级别的人交谈时，
or you're in a professional situation.
或者你处于展业场合时。
That's when you use a formal tone.
这时你就需要使用正式语调。
And then informal is when you're speaking to maybe a group of friends.
而非正式的情况是当你与一群朋友交谈时，
I don't actually speak Spanish, but my dad does and
我实际上不会说西班牙语，但是我父亲会说，
he says that this is correct.
他说这是正确的。
So for the next example, we're going to pretend that we're in charge of
那么，对于接下来的例子，我们将假装自己负责管理
a multinational e-commerce company.
一家跨国电商公司。
And so the user messages are going to be in all different languages.
因此，用户的消息将会是各种不同的语言。
And so users are going to be telling us about their IT issues in
用户将告诉我们他们在各种不同语言中的IT问题。
a wide variety of languages.
各种不同的语言。
So we need a universal translator.
所以我们需要一种通用翻译器。
So first, we'll just paste in a list of user messages in
所以，首先我们将在列表中粘贴一些用户留言。
a variety of different languages.
这些留言是用各种不同的语言书写的。
And now we will loop through each of these user messages.
现在，我们将循环遍历每个用户留言。
So for issue in user messages.
对于每个用户留言，我们将执行以下操作。
And then I'm going to copy over this slightly longer code block.
然后，我将复制这个稍微长一点的代码块。
And so the first thing we'll do is ask the model to
首先，我们要让模型告诉我们
tell us what language the issue is in.
这个问题用的是哪种语言。
So here's the prompt.
以下是提示。
Then we'll print out the original message's language and the issue.
然后，我们将打印出原始信息的语种和问题。
And then we'll ask the model to translate it into English and Korean.
接下来，我们将让模型将其翻译成英语和韩语。
So let's run this.
现在我们运行代码。
So the original message in French.
原文是法语。
So we have a variety of languages and
我们有各种语种，
then the model translates them into English and then Korean.
然后模型将其翻译成英语和韩语。
And you can kind of see here, so the model says, this is French.
你可以看到，模型显示这是法语。
So that's because the response from this prompt is going to be, this is French.
这是因为此提示的响应将是“这是法语”。
You could try editing this prompt to say something like, tell me what language this
你可以尝试编辑此提示，比如说，“告诉我这是什么语言”。
is, respond with only one word, or don't use a sentence, that kind of thing.
并只用一个单词回答，或者不使用完整的句子等等。
If you wanted this to just be kind of one word.
如果你只想让它回答一个单词。
Or you could kind of ask for it in a JSON format or something like that,
或者你可以请求以JSON格式或类似的方式进行。
which would probably encourage it to not use a whole sentence.
这可能会促使它不使用完整的句子。
And so, amazing, you've just built a universal translator.
太棒了，你刚刚建立了一个通用翻译器。
And also feel free to pause the video and
你也可以随意暂停视频，
add kind of any other languages you want to try here.
添加你想要尝试的任何其他语言。
Maybe languages you speak yourself and see how the model does.
也许是你自己会说的语言，看看模型的表现如何。
So the next thing we're going to dive into is tone transformation.
接下来，我们将深入探讨语调转换。
Writing can vary based on kind of an intended audience.
写作风格可能会根据目标受众的不同而有所变化。
The way that I would write an email to a colleague or a professor is obviously
我给同事或教授写电子邮件的方式显然会有所不同，
going to be quite different to the way I text my younger brother.
我和给我年幼的兄弟发短信的方式也会有很大区别。
And so, ChatGPT can actually also help produce different tones.
因此，ChatGPT实际上也可以帮助产生不同的语调。
So let's look at some examples.
让我们看一些例子。
So in this first example,
在这第一个例子中，
the prompt is translate the following from slang to a business letter.
提示是将以下俚语翻译成商业信函。
Dude, this is Joe, check out this spec on the standing lamp.
伙计，我是乔，看看这盏落地灯的规格。
So let's execute this.
让我们执行这个。
And as you can see, we have a much more formal business letter
正如你所看到的，我们有了一封更正式的商业信函
with a proposal for a standing lamp specification.
其中有一个站立灯规格的建议书。
The next thing that we're going to do is to convert between different formats.
我们接下来要做的是在不同格式之间进行转换。
ChatGPT is very good at translating between different formats such as JSON to
ChatGPT非常擅长在不同的格式之间进行翻译，例如JSON到
HTML, XML, all kinds of things, markdown.
HTML、XML、各种各样的，还有Markdown。
And so in the prompt, we'll describe both the input and the output formats.
因此在提示中，我们将描述输入和输出格式。
So here is an example.
这是一个例子。
So we have this JSON that contains
因此我们有这个包含以下内容的JSON
a list of restaurant employees with their name and email.
餐厅员工名单及其姓名和电子邮件。
And then in the prompt,
然后在提示中，
we're going to ask the model to translate this from JSON to HTML.
我们要求模型将这个JSON翻译成HTML。
So the prompt is translate the following Python dictionary from JSON to
提示是将以下Python字典从JSON翻译成
an HTML table with column headers and titles.
一个带有列标题和标题的HTML表格。
And then we'll get the response from the model and print it.
然后模型做出响应并将其打印出来。
So here we have some HTML displaying all of the employee names and emails.
所以这里我们有一些HTML，显示所有员工的姓名和电子邮件。
And so now let's see if we can actually view this HTML.
那么现在让我们看看我们是否可以实际查看这个HTML。
So we're going to use this display function from this Python library,
我们将使用这个Python库中的display函数，
display HTML response.
显示HTML。
And here you can see that this is a properly formatted HTML table.
在这里，你可以看到这是一个格式正确的HTML表格。
The next transformation task we're going to do is spell check and grammar checking.
我们接下来要做的转换任务是拼写检查和语法检查。
And this is a really kind of popular use for ChatGPT.
这是ChatGPT的一种非常受欢迎的用途。
I highly recommend doing this.
我强烈推荐这样做。
I do this all the time.
我一直在做这个。
And it's especially useful when you're working in a non-native language.
当你使用非母语语言工作时，这尤其有用。
And so here are some examples of some kind of common grammar and
这里是一些常见的语法和拼写问题的例子，
spelling problems and how the language model can help address these.
以及语言模型如何帮助解决这些问题。
So I'm going to paste in a list of sentences that have some kind of
我将粘贴一些具有某种语法或拼写错误的句子列表。
grammatical or spelling errors.
语法或拼写错误。
And then we're going to loop through each of these sentences.
然后我们将循环遍历这些句子中的每一个。
And ask the model to proofread these.
并要求模型校对这些句子。
Proofread and correct.
校对和纠正。
And then we'll use some delimiters.
然后我们将使用一些分隔符。
And then we will get the response and print it as usual.
模型做出响应，并像往常一样将其打印出来。
And so the model is able to correct all of these grammatical errors
就这样，这个模型能够纠正所有这些语法错误
We could use some of the techniques that we've discussed before
我们可以使用我们之前讨论过的一些技巧
So to improve the prompt, we could say proofread and correct the following text
为了改进提示，我们可以说校对和纠正以下文字
And rewrite
并重写
And rewrite the whole
并重写整个
And rewrite it
并重写
Corrected version
改正后的版本
If you don't find any errors, just say no errors found
如果你没有发现任何错误，就说没有发现错误
Let's try this
让我们来试试这个
So this way we were able to, oh, they're still using quotes here
这种方式我们能够，哦，他们在这里仍然使用引号
But you can imagine you'd be able to find a way with a little bit of
但你可以想象，你能够找到一种方法，用一点点的
iterative prompt development to
迭代提示开发
kind of find a prompt that works more reliably every single time
找到一种更可靠的提示方式，每一次都能正常工作
And so now we'll do another example
现在我们将实现另一个例子
It's always useful to check your text before you post it in a public forum
在你把你的文本发布到公共论坛之前，检查它总是有用的
And so we'll go through an example of checking a review
我们将通过一个检查评论的例子
And so here is a review about a stuffed panda
这里有一个关于毛绒熊猫的评论
And so we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct the review
我们将要求模型校对和纠正评论
Great. So we have this corrected version
很好。所以我们有了这个更正的版本
And one cool thing we can do is find
我们可以做的一件很酷的事情是找到
the kind of differences between our original review and the model's output
我们的原始评论和模型的输出之间的差异
So we're going to use this red lines Python package to do this
我们要基于这个redlines Python库来做这个
And we're going to get the diff between
我们得到以下的差异
the original text of our review and the model output
我们评论的原文和模型的输出之间的差异
and then display this
然后显示这个
And so here you can see the diff between the original review
所以在这里你可以看到原始评论和模型输出之间的差异
and the model output and the kind of things that have been corrected
和模型输出之间的差异，以及那些已经被纠正的东西
So the prompt that we use was proofread and correct this review
我们使用的提示是校对和纠正这个评论
But you can also make kind of more dramatic changes
但你也可以做一些更戏剧性的改变
kind of changes to tone and that kind of thing
语调的变化，以及诸如此类的事情
So let's try one more thing
让我们再试一试
So in this prompt, we're going to ask the model to proofread and correct
所以在这个提示中，我们将要求模特校对和纠正
the same review, but also make it more compelling and ensure that it
同样的评论，但也要使其更有说服力，并确保其
follows APA style and targets an advanced reader
遵循APA风格，并针对高级读者
And we're also going to ask for the output in markdown format
我们还将要求以Markdown格式输出结果
And so we're using the same text from the original review up here
我们在这里使用原始审查的相同文本
So let's execute this
让我们来执行这个
And here we have a expanded APA style review of the soft Panda
在这里，我们有一个扩展的APA风格的毛绒熊猫的评论
So this is it for the transforming video
这是它的转换视频
Next up, we have expanding where we'll take a shorter prompt
接下来，我们将使用扩写功能，采取较短的提示
and kind of generate a longer, more freeform response from a language model.
并从语言模型中产生一个更长、更自由的反应